today we are looking at inducement this
is a very important topic that will help
you take a well refined entries from the
exem points and avoid the traps Market
places on the chat we're going to go to
the screen now and I'll will show you
how to point them out and also how to
avoid them you know the joke guys let's
head to the chat all right Traders we're
going to start today by pointing out the
meaning of inducement first I've been
able to draft out a quick explanation on
what inducement means and this is what
we have here inducement levels are areas
in the Market where liquidity is
engineered to leure Traders into making
wrong decision often leading to stop
hunts before the real move happens
understanding and avoiding them is
crucial in smart money concept trading
so like I said that this is a simple
topic but very important because most
Traders you can see what we have here he
Traders into making the wrong decision
often leading to stop hunts before the
real move happens so if you don't
understand and also learn how to avid
void this most of the times you may see
yourself taking entries from inducement
levels and then Market will clear you
before moving to your direction that is
where you will see price stopping you
out and then moving to your direction
and you may be wondering what is going
on exactly and I know you must have seen
something like this let me quickly give
an illustration before we go to the chat
let's say you pointed out a break of
structure like this and you're waiting
for prize following our strategy you're
waiting for priz to come back into this
particular Zone and then when prize was
about to come back into the zone we got
another break of structure to the upside
most of the times this level is what
shows up as the inducement and some
Traders may think okay this is a new
structure let them start buying from
here and at the end of the day price May
tap in you know behave as if it's about
to move to your direction and then clear
you out to go to the white point and
then move to the intended Direction so
in today's video you're going to learn
how to actually avoid this and also Che
it from the right Point sometimes price
can come to inducement and then push and
keep going but what you need to ask
yourself is if I keep taking TRS from
inducement all the time how will my
trading results be so we're going to go
to the chat now and I'll show you guys
how to point that out so I was able to
back test gold from jry so let's go to
the extreme level so from here I was
able to point out where inducement
showed up on the chart how it tricked
Traders and what actually happened so
I'm going to show you guys how I pointed
them out and also how you can avoid now
this is the first one on the list so
from here we got a break of structure
following our strategy this is the
origin we'll be waiting for price to tap
into before you know moving to our
direction and you can see priz inde came
back into that origin and then dished
out a massive push to the upside but
then what happened before that we got
this break of structure now from this
point this was where price you know was
trying to retrace back into this origin
and from there it created a new break of
structure to the upside now this new
break of structure has created an
inducement and most Traders will map
this out thinking it's the right demand
Zone that this one is no longer valid
and you can see price tapped in there
dished out little movement to the upside
giving everyone hope that the movement
is about to take off from here and then
price retraced cleared everyone out this
forming an inducement liquidity cleared
everyone out and then tapped into the
white origin before dishing out the
massive push to the upside now when you
see this how will you know the one that
is an inducement and the one that is not
an inducement that is when you pick up
your FIB Two And now when picking up
your FIB two look at the point where
price took off from and where it
retraced from so now this is a buying
scenario here we're going to start from
this swing low to the swing high now any
origin that is around 0.5 or
0.618 is an inducement level you need to
pay attention to the level or the origin
that is around 0.79 which is this one
that that is the premium or the discount
level now that we are buying that is the
discount level and that is where you
wait for price to tap into before going
to your direction it requires patience
most Traders they don't want to wait and
a lot of them will get LED in into this
particular Zone and then price will
clear everyone now inducement shows up
because price wants to generate
liquidity before bringing out the
intended movement so stay away from
inducement levels or you will fall into
all the traps Market will create so
going further this was a work of
structure you can see levels price did
not come back into this particular
origin so if I'm to take drad from this
particular level now this is the point
I'll be looking to take drad from and
you can also see that an inducement
level has been created here so I'm not
going to pay attention to this I will
only point this out as my liquidity
level and I'll be waiting for price to
come here but you can see price didn't
come back to this particular level so
let's keep moving forward now this is
another example we got this break of
structure and after getting this
impulsive movement a clean break of
structure and then before price came
back into the origin look at what was
happening above here we also got another
break of structure to the upside that is
a b another break of structure to the
upside now a lot of shers would also
want to take a buy from here so you can
see price tapped in and this out tiny
movement but inde did retraced all the
way down to the main origin before
dishing out the correct movement so
moving forward I still mapped the out
this is another example a break of
structure here this is a tiny one and
then we also have another break of
structure at this level so this
particular point will trick a lot of
Traders into taking a buy here thinking
that this level is no longer valid and
price may not come back to that level
and you can see what happened price
tapped in you know the funny thing is
that price will always tap in and then
behave as see it's about to push to your
direction and then it will clear you out
because a lot of Traders will place
their buy here stop loss a little bit
below which simply means a lot of
liquidity will be sitting here and you
can see how we cleared everyone out
before dishing out the main movement so
remember all you just need to do is pick
your Fe to put it from the swing low to
the swing high if it's a cell you put it
from the swing High to the swing low and
then pay attention to the origin that is
around
0.79 let me quickly show you guys my fif
settings so that you can also use that
to set yours so this is my fif settings
you can see all so this is my fif
settings you can see everything I turned
done which is this one so quickly take a
screenshot and then set your so let's
keep moving forward we also have another
inducement level here still same example
so this being the origin that caused
this particular break of structure we
got a break of structure here to the
upside this particular level tricked a
lot of treaders into placing a buy and
then price ended up coming back into the
white origin and dishing out the right
movement now another thing you need to
point out is you can see the type of
movement price dishes out whenever it
Taps into the right origin and type of
movement it brings out when price is
reacting from an inducement level so the
right origin will always push out the
massive movement to the direction we are
looking at and then the inducement level
will just dish out the little movement
just to trick Traders into thinking that
that level will hold and then it will
clear you out this is also another
example here a break of structure and
then fvg here price tapped into an fvg
and also pushed to the direction but
that's not what we we looking at you
should pay attention to the inducement
level price also created here now you
can see the massive breakout structure
here a lot of Traders will be placing
their buys here waiting for price to
come and push to the upside from this
point and you can see how everyone you
know got cleared out and price returned
back into the extreme level and still
pushed to the direction so you can also
see what we have here same thing break
of structure you map out the origin then
prize created an inducement level here
also have it in mind that all these
inducement levels are also form of
liquidity because once they are present
they are liquidities that you should
wait for price to sweep before tapping
into your origin so I have a lot of them
here so you can also see a break of
structure price tapped into the right
origin clearing out the inducement you
can see the inducement level here a
break of structure price tapped into the
inducement level DED out a little
movement and cleared another one break
of structure inducement level created
price tapped in a little movement
cleared it to the down out side and then
pushed to the direction after tapping
into the right origin same thing here
now this is the current now this is the
current point I'll be waiting to sell XA
USD as I'm shooting this video so you
can see the inducement level price has
also created a break of structure to the
downside so I won't be looking to sell
from here instead I'll be looking to
sell from here so this is more like my
liquidity point because I'm seeing this
as an inment inj justement liquidity so
I'm expecting price to clear everything
here tap me in and still push to my
direction so that is how simple you keep
it avoid the rush avoid the rush once
you point out liquidity or inducement
levels wait for price to get to the
right origin don't try to rush them to
catch the movement don't rush to lose
money use your F to when there a lot of
Origins and then use the origin that is
very close to
0.79 that is how you can keep it simple
wait for price to sweep liquidity before
tapping into your origin all right guys
so take it easy thanks for watching and
make sure you practice understand the
strategy well before you start trading
in your life account proper risk
management is always advised so if you
want to get my C it's very simple check
the description you will see my WhatsApp
number there you can message me or you
can visit the website bye for now I'll
see you on the next one